Guide to the Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records 1939-1994 (bulk 1968-1985) MS 3009-RG 17
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records
1939-1994 (bulk 1968-1985)
MS 3009-RG 17
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
31.0 Linear feet (31 boxes)
The Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records document employee relations, benefits, participation in unions, and Time Inc.'s efforts to create or implement personnel policies and guidelines.
Time, inc.
Scope and Contents Note
The Time Inc. Administration, Human Resources and Personnel Records span from 1939 to the 1990s and include files from Rosemarie Di Sapio, Director of Administration; Robert Steed, Vice President, Personnel Director; and John Bingle, Vice President, Human Resources. Many of the files from 1939 through the 1950s look like they were retained or collected for reference reasons.
Topics include Time Inc. budgets and budgets for the Human Resources and Personnel departments; Time Inc. strategic plans; union negotiations and contracts; transitioning employees during business mergers and takeovers such as with the Washington Star; agenda and materials from the Compensation Policy Committee and Administrative Committee; compensation plans; employee stock ownership plans; healthcare management proposals; implementation of databases or other systems; insurance summaries; pension plans; memoranda discussing implementation or changes of benefits and bonuses; summer internships; Equal Employment Opportunities (EEO) changes; marketing materials from outside sources; Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) forms; and employee handbooks.
While HR and Personnel are not the offices of record for some materials (budgets, strategic plans), these materials are retained here in the event they are the only record.
Because of the limited date range for these records, it is possible earlier records related to personnel matters were interfiled into RG 1: Subject Files, RG 2: Bio Files or RG 3: Reference Files. The majority of Human Resources and Personnel records created after the mid-1980s may have been handled using the retention policies established at that time and never archived.
Arrangement Note
Organized into four series:
Series I. Administration: Director of Administration: Rosemarie Di Sapio Files
Series II. Human Resources and Personnel: General Office Files
Series III. Personnel: Vice President and Director: Robert M. Steed Files
Series IV. Human Resources: Vice President: John R. Bingle Files
Related Archival Materials Note
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. records and are currently unprocessed. Additional personnel policies and records may be in the Reference files (MS 3009.RG 3).
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of Series I, Series III.E, and other restricted materials. Restricted materials include privileged attorney correspondence; student records; medical records; personnel performance or evaluations; contracts and agreements; and records with personally identifiable information. Restricted materials are located in boxes 645 to 647 and R6 to R8. Materials created within the past 35 years also may be subject to restriction on a case-by-case basis.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Historical Note
In 1949, the Personnel Department existed independently within Time Inc. with Edward Rhett as its director. Within the department are staff position for Employee Records and Benefits, Interviewing, Orientation, and Medical.
By 1960, Personnel added staff to oversee the central files. Outside of the Personnel Department, Time Inc. created a position for Corporate Staff Relations. Louis Gratz occupied this position in the 1960 department heads directory.
By 1970, the directory lists the Personnel Office under Corporate overseen by Vice President of Administration and International Charles Bear. The Medical Office has separated from Personnel, but is an administrative unit overseen by Bear. Within Personnel, Charles Gleason, Jr. is the Vice President and Personnel Director, and William Trent is the Assistant Director. Other staff position remain the same as in the 1960 directory.
By 1980, the directory lists the Personnel Office under Corporate Administration with Robert Steed as Director and Deane Raley as Associate Director. The Medical Director is part of Personnel again. Personnel has added Affirmative Action Officers, a Director of Staff Development, and Employment Counselors.
The 1986 Management Directory lists Human Resources (HR) and Administration as separate departments under the Corporate Group, both overseen by the Chief Administrative Officer. HR has Directors of Affirmative Action, Benefits, Compensation, and a Medical Department. Rosemarie Di Sapio is Director of Administration, and Administration includes a Manager of Personnel.
A memo in Dave Maness's files states that John Bingle is Steed's successor.
Appraisal Note
Due to the permanent restrictions on the materials, one box of records from the Medical Department has been removed and returned to Time Inc.
Bingle, John R.; Di Sapio, Rosemarie; Steed, Robert M.; Administrative records; Corporation records; Corporations--History; Corporations--New York (State)--New York; Labor unions--New York (State)--New York.; Newspaper Guild of New York; Personnel departments -- New York (State) -- New York; Personnel records; Publishers and publishing--New York (State)--New York; Time, inc. -- Employees
- Series I. Administration: Director of Administration: Rosemarie Di Sapio Files [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2069], 1987-1994; 2.0 Linear feet (2 boxes) (Offsite-box 646-647)
  Scope and Contents Note
  The personnel files kept by Rosemarie Di Sapio's office include performance reviews and termination agreements and payouts.
  Arrangement Note
  Organized alphabetically.
- Series II: Human Resources and Personnel: General Office Files, 1974-1989; 3.0 Linear feet (3 boxes)
  The General Office Files contain unorganized materials filed with the rest of the Human Resources and Personnel files, but are not specific to any person's office.
  - Applicant Flow Project, 1979-1982 (Offsite-box 625)
    The Applicant Flow Project includes impact reports, applicant data, interview record sheets and other reports regarding demographics for each department at Time Inc. It looks like statistics that Human Resources collected in the event they needed to report to the U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC).
  - Budget: Time Inc.: 1974-1982 (Offsite-box 626)
  - Employee Benefits Handbooks: 1984, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 627, Folder 1-3)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission (Offsite-box 627, Folder 4-5)
  - Strategic Plan: 1981-1985 (Offsite-box 627, Folder 6)
- Series III: Personnel: Vice President and Director: Robert M. Steed Files, 1939-1985 (bulk 1968-1985); 24.0 Linear feet (24 boxes)
  Organized into seven subseries:
  Subseries III.A. General Office Files Subseries III.B. Benefits Subseries III.C. Human Resources Staff Subseries III.D. International Subseries III.E. Situations Subseries III.F. Subsidiaries Subseries III.G. Union Relations
  The groups of files in this series were found housed together and the primary correspondent is Robert "Bob" M. Steed, Vice President, Personnel Director. The largest run of alphabetically grouped files are designated as general office files while smaller groupings address specific topics or areas of the company. His files document changes in Time Inc. benefits, compensation, employment policies and guidelines; directories and staff lists; and personnel statistics.
  - Subseries III.A: General Office Files, 1945-1984 (bulk 1968-1984); 11.8 Linear feet (12 boxes)
    The General Office Files include a range of topics handled by Human Resources and Personnel including changes in employment law; medical and life insurance; leave policies; other benefits such as education reimbursement, day care and adoption; fair hiring practices; compensation and pensions; the movement of staff within the organization; and staff surveys.
    - Administrative Committee: Pension plan (Offsite-box 630)
    - Administrative Committee: Pension plan [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Administrative Committee: Profit-sharing (Offsite-box 630)
    - Administrative Committee: Profit-sharing [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Adoptions (Offsite-box 630)
    - Adoptions [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Alcoholism and drugs (Offsite-box 630, Folder 4-5)
    - Alumni society (Offsite-box 630, Folder 6)
    - Areas of emphasis (Offsite-box 630, Folder 7)
    - ATC [American Television and Communications Corporation] (Offsite-box 630, Folder 8-9)
    - Analyses: Age, service and compensation (Offsite-box 630, Folder 10)
    - Annual reports: 1970 and later (Offsite-box 630, Folder 11-13)
    - Application forms (Offsite-box 630, Folder 14)
    - Appraisals: Evaluations (Offsite-box 630, Folder 15)
    - Attitude survey (Offsite-box 630, Folder 16)
    - Benefits: Deferred compensation plans (Offsite-box 630, Folder 17)
    - Benefits: Financial audit (Offsite-box 630, Folder 18)
    - Benefits: General (Offsite-box 630, Folder 19)
    - Benefits: Memos (Offsite-box 630, Folder 20)
    - Blood drive (Offsite-box 630, Folder 21)
    - Board of directors (Offsite-box 630, Folder 22-23)
    - BOMC [Book-of-the-Month Club] (Offsite-box 630, Folder 24)
    - Bonus: Executive (Offsite-box 630, Folder 25-26)
    - Bonus: Deferred bonus program (Offsite-box 630, Folder 27)
    - Bonus: 1984 Bonus process (Offsite-box 630, Folder 28)
    - Bonus: 1980 Bonus plans study (Offsite-box 630-631)
    - Bonus: 1981 (Offsite-box 631, Folder 2)
    - Bonus: Corporate incentive bonus program: Salary adjustment: 1980 (Offsite-box 631, Folder 3)
    - Bonus: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 631, Folder 4)
    - Bonus: Corporate incentive: 1981 (Offsite-box 631, Folder 5)
    - Budget (Offsite-box 631, Folder 6-7)
    - Business roundtable (Offsite-box 631, Folder 8-9)
    - Cable deregulation (Offsite-box 631, Folder 10)
    - Capital appropriations procedures (Offsite-box 631, Folder 11)
    - Cardio fitness systems (Offsite-box 631)
    - Cardio fitness systems [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Change of control (Offsite-box 631, Folder 13)
    - Chicago directory (Offsite-box 631, Folder 14)
    - Chicago relocation task force (Offsite-box 631, Folder 15)
    - Chicago: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 631)
    - Chicago: Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Club memberships (Offsite-box 631, Folder 17)
    - Communications (Offsite-box 631, Folder 18)
    - Communications personnel group (Offsite-box 631, Folder 19)
    - Community relations (Offsite-box 631, Folder 20)
    - Compensation: Flexible (Offsite-box 631, Folder 21)
    - Compensation: Personnel and Compensation Committee (Offsite-box 631, Folder 22)
    - Compensation: Compensation and benefit expense [empty] (Offsite-box 631, Folder 23)
    - Compensation: Incentive (Offsite-box 631, Folder 24)
    - Compensation: Information: Top management (Offsite-box 631, Folder 25)
    - Compensation: Review (Offsite-box 631, Folder 26-28)
    - Compensation: Snow day (Offsite-box 631, Folder 29)
    - Compensation: Study (Offsite-box 631, Folder 30)
    - Computer room move (Offsite-box 631, Folder 31)
    - Conflict of interest (Offsite-box 631, Folder 32)
    - Consultants (Offsite-box 631-632)
    - Consumer price index (Offsite-box 632, Folder 2)
    - Contract employees [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Contributions committee (Offsite-box 632, Folder 3)
    - Contributions and drives (Offsite-box 632, Folder 4)
    - Corporate cardio fitness systems (Offsite-box 632)
    - Corporate cardio fitness systems [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Corporate identity (Offsite-box 632, Folder 6)
    - Corporate incentive bonus plan (Offsite-box 632, Folder 7)
    - Corrupt Practices Act (Offsite-box 632, Folder 8)
    - Cost Control Committee (Offsite-box 632, Folder 9)
    - CRT (Cathode ray tube) (Offsite-box 632, Folder 10)
    - Counseling: Financial (Offsite-box 632, Folder 11)
    - Data processing (Offsite-box 632, Folder 12)
    - Day care (Offsite-box 632, Folder 13)
    - DELTA (Offsite-box 632, Folder 14)
    - Department head directories (Offsite-box 632, Folder 15-17)
    - Distribution lists (Offsite-box 632, Folder 18)
    - Education benefits (Offsite-box 632, Folder 19)
    - Electronic publishing (Offsite-box 632, Folder 20)
    - Employee communications (Offsite-box 632, Folder 21)
    - Employee handbooks (Offsite-box 632, Folder 22)
    - Employee opinion survey (Offsite-box 632-633)
    - Employment (Offsite-box 633)
    - Employment [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Endorsements: Employee (Offsite-box 633, Folder 4)
    - Entertainment industry survey (Offsite-box 633, Folder 5)
    - Equal opportunity (Offsite-box 633)
    - Equal opportunity [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Equal Time (Offsite-box 633, Folder 7)
    - ESOP (Offsite-box 633)
    - ESOP [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Excess benefits plan (Offsite-box 633, Folder 10)
    - Evaluations memo: 1/78 (Offsite-box 633, Folder 11)
    - Executive compensation (Offsite-box 633, Folder 12)
    - Executive education (Offsite-box 633, Folder 13-14)
    - Executive exchange program (Offsite-box 633, Folder 15)
    - Executive life insurance (Offsite-box 633, Folder 16)
    - Executive search (Offsite-box 633, Folder 17)
    - Films [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Financial data processing (Offsite-box 633, Folder 18)
    - 541 (Chicago office) (Offsite-box 633)
    - 541 (Chicago office) [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - 541 (Chicago office) reorganization (Offsite-box 633, Folder 20)
    - Five year plan (Offsite-box 633, Folder 21)
    - Flexible benefits (Offsite-box 633, Folder 22-23)
    - 401(k) (Offsite-box 633, Folder 24)
    - Garnishments (Offsite-box 633, Folder 25)
    - Gay rights (Offsite-box 633, Folder 26)
    - General increase (Offsite-box 633, Folder 27)
    - Government record keeping (Offsite-box 633, Folder 28)
    - Handy Associates, Inc.: Executive recruitment/Incentive compensation (Offsite-box 633, Folder 29)
    - HBO organization charts (Offsite-box 633, Folder 30)
    - Headcount (Offsite-box 633, Folder 31)
    - Heiskell award (Offsite-box 633-634)
    - Histories, Time Inc. (printed brochures) (Offsite-box 634, Folder 2-3)
    - Holidays (Offsite-box 634)
    - Holidays [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Home Buyers' Assistance Corp (Offsite-box 634, Folder 6)
    - Human Resources Development Group (Offsite-box 634, Folder 7-8)
    - IBM survey (Offsite-box 634, Folder 9)
    - Immigration (Offsite-box 634, Folder 10)
    - Individual retirement accounts (Offsite-box 634, Folder 11)
    - Information systems department (Offsite-box 634, Folder 12)
    - Information systems executive (Offsite-box 634, Folder 13)
    - Information systems group: 1983 personnel statistics (Offsite-box 634, Folder 14)
    - Instant Newyorker (Offsite-box 634, Folder 15)
    - Insurance: Accident (Offsite-box 634, Folder 16)
    - Insurance: Disability (Offsite-box 634, Folder 17)
    - Insurance: Executive life (Offsite-box 634, Folder 18)
    - Insurance: Life (Offsite-box 634)
    - Insurance: Life [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Insurance: Medical/Dental (Offsite-box 634, Folder 21)
    - Insurance: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 634)
    - Insurance: Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - International Executive Service Corps (Offsite-box 634, Folder 23)
    - Introductory Course in Supervision (Offsite-box 634, Folder 24)
    - Labor relations office (Offsite-box 634, Folder 25)
    - Last day worked (Offsite-box 634, Folder 26)
    - Leaves: Maternity (Offsite-box 634)
    - Leaves: Maternity [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Leaves: Paternity (Offsite-box 634, Folder 28)
    - Leaves: Sabbatical (Offsite-box 634, Folder 29)
    - Leaves: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 634)
    - Leaves: Miscellaneous [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Leaves: Sickness (Offsite-box 634, Folder 31)
    - Legal department (Offsite-box 634, Folder 32)
    - Length of service (Offsite-box 634, Folder 33)
    - Life (Offsite-box 634, Folder 34)
    - Loan committee (Offsite-box 634)
    - Loan committee [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Locations list (Offsite-box 634, Folder 36)
      This lists the cities and states of businesses operated by Time Inc.
    - [Management] Back up (Offsite-box 634, Folder 37)
    - Management development: Columbia University program for executives (Offsite-box 634)
    - Management development: Columbia University program for executives [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Management development: Harvard program (Offsite-box 634)
    - Management development: Harvard program [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Management development: AMP [Harvard] [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Management development: Strategy (Offsite-box 635, Folder 1-2)
    - Management development: [General]: 1978- (Offsite-box 635, Folder 3)
    - Management development: Soundview executive book summaries (Offsite-box 635, Folder 4)
    - Management inventory (Offsite-box 635, Folder 5-7)
    - Management training (in-house) (Offsite-box 635, Folder 8)
    - Managing editors (Offsite-box 635, Folder 9)
    - Managing organizational effectiveness Harvard program (Offsite-box 635, Folder 10)
    - Managing professional growth (Offsite-box 635, Folder 11)
    - Matching grants (Offsite-box 635, Folder 12)
    - Maternity leave (Offsite-box 635, Folder 13)
    - McAlinden Associates, Inc. (Offsite-box 635, Folder 14)
    - McKinsey study (Offsite-box 635, Folder 15-16)
    - Meal allowances (Offsite-box 635, Folder 17)
    - Medical department: Health maintenance organization (Offsite-box 635, Folder 18)
    - Medical department: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 635, Folder 19)
    - Medical department: Sick leave reports [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Minority business development (Offsite-box 635, Folder 20)
    - Minority Forum (Offsite-box 635, Folder 21-23)
    - Mission statement (Offsite-box 635, Folder 24)
    - Mortgage differential policy (Offsite-box 635, Folder 25)
    - Moving studies (Offsite-box 635, Folder 26)
      Primarily related to Time's proposed office move with some records about new employee moving costs.
    - National Alliance of Business (Offsite-box 635, Folder 27)
    - "Negroes" [African Americans]: Civil Rights Act (1964) (Offsite-box 635, Folder 28)
    - "Negroes" [African Americans]: Harlem Street Academies (Offsite-box 635, Folder 29)
    - "Negroes" [African Americans]: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 636, Folder 1)
      Includes copies of 1940s laws and policies related to anti-discrimination.
    - Newspaper Guild (Offsite-box 636, Folder 2)
    - New Time Inc., The (Offsite-box 636, Folder 3)
    - New York City partnership (Offsite-box 636, Folder 4)
    - New York data center (Offsite-box 636, Folder 5)
    - Occupational Health and Safety - OSHA (Offsite-box 636, Folder 6)
    - Ombudsman (Offsite-box 636, Folder 7)
    - Opinion research survey (Offsite-box 636, Folder 8-9)
    - Organization chart - Books (Offsite-box 636, Folder 10)
    - Organizational effectiveness study (Offsite-box 636, Folder 11)
    - Outplacement (Offsite-box 636, Folder 12)
    - Overtime (Offsite-box 636)
    - Overtime [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Overtime - 1983 study (Offsite-box 636)
    - Overtime - 1983 study [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Parties and gifts (Offsite-box 636, Folder 16)
      Includes collected policies from 1952 to 1967.
    - Part-time and requisition employees (Offsite-box 636)
    - Part-time and requisition employees [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Payroll (Offsite-box 636, Folder 18-19)
    - Pension plan - Unfunded liabilities (Offsite-box 636, Folder 20)
    - Pension Reform Act (Offsite-box 636, Folder 21)
    - Pension tax reform (Offsite-box 636, Folder 22)
    - Perquisites - Executive (Offsite-box 636, Folder 23)
    - Personnel: Budget (Offsite-box 636-637)
    - Personnel: Budget presentations (Offsite-box 637, Folder 2)
    - Personnel: 5 year plan (Offsite-box 637, Folder 3)
    - Personnel: Handbooks (Offsite-box 637, Folder 4)
    - Personnel: Human resource development (Offsite-box 637, Folder 5)
    - Personnel: Human resource strategy (Offsite-box 637, Folder 6)
    - Personnel: Incentive program (Offsite-box 637)
    - Personnel: Incentive program [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Personnel: Information systems comptrollers EP&B system: Pisces (Offsite-box 637)
      Records regarding the implementation of human resources software.
    - Personnel: Information systems comptrollers EP&B system: Pisces [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Personnel: Planning (Offsite-box 637, Folder 13)
    - Personnel: Reorganization (Offsite-box 637, Folder 14)
    - Personnel: Statistics (Offsite-box 637, Folder 15)
    - Personnel: Training program (Offsite-box 637, Folder 16)
    - Personnel: Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 637, Folder 17)
    - Policy (Offsite-box 637, Folder 18)
    - Political activity (Offsite-box 637, Folder 19)
    - Porcell, Marsha [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Posting [empty] (Offsite-box 637, Folder 20)
    - Pregnancy Discrimination Act (Offsite-box 637)
    - Pregnancy Discrimination Act [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - The President's Executive Exchange Program for Business Executives (Offsite-box 637, Folder 22)
    - Privacy (Offsite-box 637)
    - Privacy [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Probationary period concept (Offsite-box 637, Folder 24)
    - Productivity (Offsite-box 637, Folder 25)
    - Profit sharing (Offsite-box 637)
    - Profit sharing [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Profit-sharing: 1979-80 (Offsite-box 637)
    - Profit-sharing: 1979-80 [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Profit-sharing historical data (Offsite-box 637, Folder 29)
    - Profit-sharing offset (Offsite-box 637, Folder 30)
    - Promotables list (Offsite-box 637, Folder 31)
    - Public speaking program (Offsite-box 637, Folder 32)
    - Record retention (Offsite-box 637)
    - Record retention [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Recruitment (Offsite-box 637, Folder 34-35)
    - Resumes - Samples (Offsite-box 637, Folder 36)
    - Retirement: Counselling (Offsite-box 637, Folder 37)
    - Retirement: Directory (Offsite-box 638, Folder 1)
    - Retirement: Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (Offsite-box 638, Folder 2)
    - Retirement: Study (Offsite-box 638, Folder 3)
    - Salary administration (Offsite-box 638, Folder 4)
    - Salary studies (Offsite-box 638, Folder 5)
    - Savings bonds - U.S. (Offsite-box 638, Folder 6)
    - Scholarships (Offsite-box 638, Folder 7)
    - Secretaries (Offsite-box 638, Folder 8)
    - Secretarial pool (Offsite-box 638, Folder 9)
    - Selling Areas-Marketing, Inc. (SAMI) (Offsite-box 638, Folder 10)
    - Severance pay and re-hires (Offsite-box 638, Folder 11)
    - Sexual harrassment (Offsite-box 638, Folder 12)
    - Sick leave report (Offsite-box 638)
    - Sick leave report [RESTRICTED] (Offsite-box R6)
    - Skills bank (Offsite-box 638, Folder 14)
    - Social Security and Medicare (Offsite-box 638, Folder 15)
    - Software publishing (Offsite-box 638, Folder 16)
    - Special bonuses (Offsite-box 638, Folder 17)
    - Speeches (Offsite-box 638, Folder 18)
    - Staff development (Offsite-box 638, Folder 19)
    - [Staff] lists (Offsite-box 638, Folder 20)
    - Sterling Institute (Offsite-box 638, Folder 21)
    - Stock bonus plan (Offsite-box 638, Folder 22)